As of this morning, you can see
that I made over $421,000 US in
just over six months without taking one
single sales call.
I, by accident, created a sales system,
which means that I can make sales at the
touch of a button and save the time
that most people spend on the phone doing
other
productive things, like this video.
There are a few main problems
that I see with taking sales calls in
2024, so let's
quickly look into them.
Problem number one, when people say no,
or they say they
need more time, or need to think about it,
or whatever reason they don't purchase
your services,
you've now wasted a pretty intense period
of time, which could've
been used doing something so much better.
There are literally 10x things
that you could do instead,
which I'll get onto in
a second. Two, people that
are ready to buy, and those of which
that are A+
grade clients,
don't particularly like taking sales
calls.
Right next to me, I have my dog, Alfie,
and he's crazy.
He's a breed of dog in Australia called a
Kelpie, and we had this problem that
every time a bike went past with a dog,
he was losing his shit. Pain point.
So I come home, look at my missus, I go,
"We need a dog trainer." I tried looking
around on Google a little bit. Instead,
I went someone that I knew would have a
good dog training knowledge in the area.
They recommended someone to me,
so I reach out.
When I reached out to this person,
he sent me a list of all of his prices on
a neat
PDF, and he said, "Let me know
which you would like,
and we can start." I looked
through it. First thing I thought was,
"Oh my God, this guy is expensive." Which
immediately made me think he was good.
And second of all,
I looked through his packages,
found one that I thought would be
perfect for us. Said,
"I'd like to do this package." He goes,
"Cool.
Send the payment,
and we'll pick a date." It's exactly how
it worked, and he was
great. However, in this process, if
that dog trainer had said,
"Hey, mate,
why don't we jump on a phone call together
and we can discover
what would be the right option for you
moving forward, and we can talk pricing on
the phone?" I would've run a mile. One,
I don't want to take a phone call.
I don't want to chat to some random dog
trainer.
I want to know what it is you offer,
how much it's going to cost me,
and I want to
get a general idea of whether
or not you're good or not.
I got those things from the PDF
that he sent me.
Therefore, I'm not wasting his time,
and he's not wasting mine.
Then there's another blatantly obvious
issue that many of you probably
not even know walking into headfirst,
and that's number three.
It's something that I call the diary
effect.
If your diary is wide open,
they know you're desperate as hell.
You've got all these calendar open slots,
8:30, 9:30.
Hold on, if this person
is quiet enough to be this available,
they cannot be good
at what they do.
We've all walked past a quiet restaurant
and thought the exact
same thing. That place must be shit.
And number four, there
are just way better ways to make sales
than jumping on a
phone call. So why is it that I despise,
hate, loathe sales calls
altogether? Well, let's rewind a second.
I used to work as a door-to-door
salesperson for a company in the UK called
NPower.
My postcode was GL1,
so I worked in Gloucester.
It was absolutely freezing, and I
was selling to people gas and electric,
and they
already had gas and electric.
I'd knock on their doors and go, "Hi,
my name's James
Smith, and I'm from NPower." They'd go,
"NPower?
I thought we were with British Gas." I'd
say, "Ha ha. Exactly.
That's why I'm here." I had doors slammed
in my face, was told to fuck off.
People thought I was there to read the
meter.
And I stuck with this job for absolute
months on end until the day that I nearly
quit. And I actually tried to quit.
I actually called up my manager,
and I said to him, "Hey, mate.
I can't do this anymore.
I'm not enjoying it.
It's absolutely freezing." I said to him,
"I'm not really enjoying this, and to be
honest,
even though I'm making all right money,
I can't see myself doing this for
much longer." My manager at the time
pulled over his car, opens his laptop.
He goes, [imitates typing] and he goes,
"James Smith, yeah?
I want you." He goes, "All right, yeah.
According to your averages,
you make one sale per 100 doors." He goes,
"It's
actually good.
It's better than most of the people in
your team." In my head, I
thought I was pretty terrible.
And he goes, "James,
can I ask you a question?
How many more sales do you need for the
day?" I said, "Two." He goes, "Do you want
my advice?" I said, "Yeah." He goes,
"Knock on 200 more fucking doors." That
was probably one of the most influential
lessons that I learned about the sales
process. For the rest of the afternoon,
I thought, instead of wanting every
door to be a yes,
instead I should just look for 100 nos
and one yes will appear.
I shouldn't get too caught up about it.
And let me tell you another thing.
Being a 21-year-old door-to-door salesman,
I often thought that one day I'd knock
on a door and some MILF would open the
door,
and maybe I would've caught her right
in the middle of a [clicks]
little home session of a masturbation.
You know where I'm going.
She might have come out in, like,
a velvety, silky dressing gown and gone,
"Listen,
you've just interrupted what I
was getting up to,
so why don't you come in here
and finish me off?" Never happened.
I did get once invited in for a cup of tea
by an old lady that had a dog with one
eye. Shit blowjob, though. Only joking.
But I learned a lot about the sales
process through knocking on doors.
I then made it into the warm
and worked in a office, which
was actually just a
sales center where I would have to cold
call companies in the IT sector, trying to
get their business.
Then I actually went to an IT security
company where I'd have
to qualify the size of different sales
opportunities.
And then I realized, actually,
a lot of the time,
this could've just been done over
email,
and I didn't particularly like calling
people, didn't like particularly
knocking on people's doors.
So I just sent them an email.
"Hey, what's the size of your business?
Are you interested?" I preferred that,
because what I came to realize was most of
the people I was emailing, they
were either interested or they weren't.
And when they got an email, they
were like, "Yes," or they were like,
"No." I was
like, "Why am I calling these people,
leaving voice notes, having them call me
back, them missing me,
me chatting to their VA?
'Hey, can I talk to...'" It
was all of this pissing around
when in one email, "Hey, we've got this.
Are you interested?" was more than enough.
I would get in trouble for over-hitting my
sales target because my phone calls
weren't high enough. "James,
you got to hit 100 calls a day." I
was like, "I've hit
my target three months early." Then after
doing the whole sales thing, went into
the world of recruitment,
and everyone said to me, "James,
if you want to work in
recruitment,
you will earn really good money,
but you'll hate it." And I was like,
"How can you earn really good money
and hate it?" And then I started
recruitment,
and I earned really good money,
and I hated it.
And the worst thing about recruitment
was many things,
but I had to wear a suit and
tie every day for, like, two years.
And this was when I got into, like,
my peak fitness phase, and I was trying to
lean up, and there was one time
that I took a load of Clenbuterol,
which is a fat
stripper.
Not like a big girl dancing on a pole,
like a stimulant, an asthma drug.
And I didn't realize we're going into
London for a meeting.
We met with a big company called Serco,
and we get in there, and I'm sweating,
right? It's the hottest day of the year.
Wrong day to take Clenbuterol.
We go in there, and I said to my boss,
I'm like, "Look,
can I take my jacket off?"
He goes,
"Only if they take their jacket off."
And that person did not take his
jacket off.
He had the heat tolerance of someone
that does a sauna three times a
day,
and I'm just sat there dripping sweat onto
my notepad.
And after that, I was like,
"I'm not doing recruitment." I'm not
wearing clothes
for the sake of wearing clothes, which
is what people in corporate do.
Like, what does a suit even do?
You have way too many pockets,
and there's too much
stress, and you've got to iron stuff.
Like, just It's not for me. Where were we?
Okay,
so in the process of trying to make you
aware that you don't need to do sales
calls,
let's do reverse engineering of the entire
sales system and structure that
I would advise for your business without
even knowing it.
We need to get people's attention.
That's what we live in right now.
It's an attention economy.
It wasn't the same
when I worked in recruitment.
But anyway, at the top, we have organic,
and we have paid content.
That's your two way of getting in front of
people.
You can pay through paid ads and do it,
or you can actually do organic and create
content,
build a social media following over time,
reputation, whatever it is.
Now, some people think
if you've got subpar, crappy content,
that you can just do
paid ads and you can skip the whole
process of having to get good at producing
and
talking to camera,
and even I will do this edit myself.
But the reality is
if you just do paid ads with poor content,
it's like trying to
polish a turd.
You're probably better off at mastering
the organic content, and
then when one post does a lot better than
all the other posts that you've done,
first of all, you say, "Why was that?
And can I imitate and replicate that?"
And two, maybe you boost the post that's
doing better than all the others.
If one post that you've done
is getting more
email addresses or it's growing your
account more than any others,
that's the one
to boost.
You don't just take a crappy post that,
"Hi, I'm selling
this. Please buy it,"
and put some money behind it
and hope for the best, because
then you have a bad experience with paid
ads.
But anyway, this isn't a paid ads video.
So once we master the ability of organic
content and maybe a little bit of paid on
top, we need to ask ourselves,
what do we do then?
Well,
we don't really want to sell to people on
social media because it's similar
to going on the dance floor on a night out
and going, "Hey, do you want to have sex
with me?" Because although
that person might want to actually have
sex with you,
they're probably going to say no,
and they're going to say no because of the
circumstances and the situation.
They've just come out with their friends,
having a good time. They're dancing.
Although they might want to have sex with
you, they would probably rather just give
you a little bit of contact information so
we can talk away from the dance floor at
another time. And the person
that walks away from the club with all
these numbers
on their phone is going to be able to
message them, take people on dates,
and from
the dates, they're going to... If we
were to look at the door-knocking days, we
could say
every 10 numbers, four dates.
Every four dates,
going to get banged twice,
whatever.
But rather than asking for their number in
this context, the best thing
we're probably going to want to do
is take their email address, and this
is where I
call it a squeeze page.
Some people call them lead magnets,
but in essence, we want
to squeeze that person in front of us for
their contact information.
Now, there's a principle in sales
that I learned from my shirt-wearing days
called
WIIFM, What's In It For Me. If there
is nothing in it for me,
I'm not going to do
it. Like this video. What's in it for me?
Well,
within the last 30 seconds of this video,
I'm going to present an offer that
you'll be silly to take up.
In the world of absolutely everything
around us, if we
do not give something of value,
we will not get anything back.
If I didn't provide people with a calorie
calculator or a free trial of my app, or
with years of content generating goodwill,
I wouldn't have got anything back from
them.
So you need to decide what to give
someone.
And now,
if you were to list out 10 problems
that your avatar faces,
which is the person you would most likely
to do business with, you could probably
strip away five that aren't that good.
You're left with five really big problems.
Now,
you could create five really big solutions
for those, and then pick which is
the easiest one to deliver,
and find a way to deliver it.
You're probably thinking I'll make a nice
PDF. Don't do PDFs, right? It's 2024.
People are sick to death of your damn
PDFs. Do something a bit more creative.
Something that's really doing well at the
moment is something called an email
autoresponder, which
is a series of emails that you get.
So let's say you sign up to a list.
Sometimes it's, "Oh, it's been seven days.
How did you..." For instance,
you're a business owner.
You probably like more sales,
probably like the ability to work remote
one day.
You probably would like the audience
that you feel like you deserve because you
work so hard. Cool. So for me,
rather than going, "Download my PDF.
I've got this PDF.
Take my PDF," it would make way more sense
for me to
say, "Hey,
why don't I give you 30 ways in 30 days to
revolutionize your business?
And I will send them to you every day via
email, and they will take no more than a
minute to read." You're going to go,
"That sounds kind of cool.
For my email address,
that's some good value.
This handsome bugger in front of me has
done quite well with his relative
businesses, so I can access
that information for just an email
address?
Wow." Well,
I'll put a link in the description for
that, but don't get distracted.
You must have something of value you can
give to someone for their email address in
return. Now,
a brief introduction to why email
marketing is probably bigger in 2024
than it was in 2014
when everyone thought it
was going to be dead. I'm at my desk.
Now,
anything that needs to be paid,
pay off my credit card,
pay my council rates,
whatever it is,
I do at my desk. So
if I get an email about something,
chances are, if I buy it,
I'm going to buy it at my desk
when I'm doing my emails.
If you try and sell to me on my phone
when I'm out and about, when I'm having a
poo, not going to happen. I've got ADHD.
Just not going to happen.
If you want my attention,
you've got to send it to me via email.
I even send myself messages via email so
that I don't forget.
We've also got something called the right
time effect that if you sell to someone
and they're just not interested at
that time, you can keep peppering them.
As long as your emails have enough value
or they're entertaining or they're fun to
read, you can just keep sending them,
and some people literally have read my
emails
for months on end before they join.
Which probably leads you on to thinking,
okay, if you're going to email them, then
what? Do we send them a Buy Now button?
No,
we send them something called a landing
page.
Now,
a landing page isn't necessarily a
website.
It's a page with one purpose,
to convert someone to buy from us.
On this page, we do not need loads
and loads of copy, loads
and loads of text.
We don't need your life story.
We certainly don't need a small book.
Ultimately,
the page must tell us what it
is they're selling, why they need it,
how much it costs, what they get,
and why they should trust us.
And in 2024,
one of the biggest things
that I think that I would recommend for
you
guys to have on your page
is something called a VSL.
It's called a video sales letter,
but really it's a header video of you
explaining
what it is that you're selling.
The second link in my description
is to my business
mentorship. Now, at the end of this video,
if you want to sniff that out, you can
have a look at not only my landing page,
but my VSL at the top, which is a
well-put-together video of me telling you
exactly what it is that I do.
So here's the beautiful thing.
If you're someone that's done sales calls
and had
them as a massive part of your regime for
ages, you know the objections that people
have.
You're almost ready for them the second
they jump on the call where you're
going to go, "Okay, cool. I get it
that you're worried about price,
you're worried
about this,
you're worried about that." You can take
every single objection from
the people that you know they have
and put it in your VSL.
I could turn around right now and go,
"Are you overworked, underpaid, and
frustrated because you haven't got a real
social media strategy to get sales for
your business? Well,
I've created a course called the No Sales
Call System that you
can implement to your business." I talk to
your problems.
And then I could say,
"I know you think that this course
is going to be too
expensive. I have a feeling
that you're going to want to talk to your
partner
first. So how about this?
I give you a money-back guarantee." You
are
dismantling the things that they have
and the objections they have, so you don't
have to get on that sales call with them.
They just need to watch the video,
and it does it for it.
It's like having a robot doing the sales
call for you.
You could then have some social proof
underneath it,
maybe some testimonials from
your clients. And I know a lot of you
are like, "Oh, but James, I'm not very
confident on the camera.
I'm not very confident on the camera."
Well, have you ever noticed,
don't know about you,
but back in my day when I was
single, when I was on Hinge or Tinder
or Bumble, whatever it was, a lot of the
girls, they look fit in pictures,
and you meet them in real life,
and you're like,
"Oh my God, you look nothing like it."
And it gave me real absolute trust
issues. And what I'd have to do is try
and find videos on their socials because
when you see someone move,
you get a better understanding for what's
going on when
you can see them move.
Here's a case in point.
Cameron Diaz and Jennifer Aniston
were not hot enough to be supermodels.
Static pictures of them,
they're still fit.
But it's only when you see them move,
it's only when you see them interact with
people, it's only
when you see them in video format
that you go, "Oh my God, these
people are beautiful." That's why a lot of
the dating world is fucked right now,
because people are-- That's the dog
that needed the trainer.
That's why the social dating world
is fucked right now, because people
are reduced down to a picture,
to a static image, when really so
much,
even the trust in you watching me right
now, telling these stories and trying
to get you away from sales calls. We
are accumulating trust, I
hope, between each other,
where I'm giving you value, and in return,
you're getting
to see me do my thing in my office,
in my home.
So when we get to the end of this landing
page, we've
hopefully created a lot of trust in
that person.
So where do we send them a link to?
To book in a sales call? No. To buy.
You shouldn't be talking to people without
having their money first.
It's just a simple principle,
because it'll make you a lot happier to
talk to them.
"Hey, John,
thank you very much for joining in.
I really appreciate you." The second I got
PayPal payments from my clients back in
the day, I'd get my phone,
I'd send them an individualized video.
"John mate, really appreciate,
glad to have you signing me up." Because
they will
have something called buyer's regret,
and buyer's regret is why so many of you,
after you've done a sales call with
someone, they message you and ask, "Okay,
sorry, I'm backtracking," whatever.
But if you get the payment first,
you can disintegrate their buyer's regret.
"Really appreciate you having here.
Can't wait to have you as part of my
program." And there's a really incredible
way
to get rid of buyer's regret,
which I'm going to get onto after this
very next
point.
The other reason you want them to buy
is because they could be ready to buy
right now. Very case in point. Yesterday,
I took my car in for service.
I love my car. Audi RS6,
best car in the world.
I don't think there
is a better car where practicality
meets...
Anyway, so I go to the service,
passes with flying colors, but they say,
"James,
you have one tire that's got one
millimeter left on it.
It's probably got a month left on it."
And I was like,
"Fuck's sake." Because I've
got ADHD, things like this will just ding,
ding, ding, ding, ding, around in my
head forever.
I'll be trying to fall asleep in two
weeks' time, and I'll go,
"James, because of your short-term memory,
don't forget you've got to get out that
tire changed." And then
if I got a flat tire,
it wouldn't just ruin my day or my
week, it would ruin my month,
because I'd go, "James,
you had the responsibility to
remember that you had one mil left on your
tire, and because you didn't remember
that,
you've now got a flat." Now I'm stuck by
the side of the road waiting for
breakdown. I don't even know
if I've got breakdown cover.
Got to get my tire replaced. I
don't know if you get towed.
Have I got a spare tire?
I don't even know if I've got a spare
tire.
So I go straight from the service place,
straight to the tire place near me.
I go there, I go, "Look,
I know there's tread left on this tire,
but I want them
both replaced.
I'll pay you now because I want this
done. I want this out my life.
I want it to be not something that's
just pinging around in my brain.
I want it dealt with." Go in there, £450
per tire. [coughs] 450. "Is
that it?" I said.
"Is that it?" But I paid for it.
They're getting put on in a couple of
days.
It's dealt with.
I don't want to get on a call with you.
I just want my problems to go away.
And I tell you what,
the second I paid £450 a
tire, I felt good. It's dealt with.
The money's gone, but my problem
is dealt with.
And that's what a lot of people
are going to be facing
when they come to you.
So don't think, "Oh,
let's book in a call for next week." No.
Let them deal with the problem
and let them pay you.
And the way that you can eradicate any
buyer's regret and make people confident
in
paying you is there's something you can do
very easily that's probably going to
five to tenfold the amount of sales you
get.
Offer them a money-back guarantee for a
week, two weeks, one month.
Because at the end of the day,
if they hate the service you've provided,
they
probably should get their money back.
You've got consumer rights in a lot of
countries where they're legally entitled
to
get it back anyway. Not to mention,
if someone has a bad experience with you
through whatever, their fault, your fault,
whatever, if you refund them, they will
only have good things to say about you.
If you don't,
you've just got poisonous people out there
that will go to your
TripAdvisor, Trustpilot,
and give you a bad review,
which you just don't want.
Not only that,
wouldn't you like the confidence to say to
someone, "Hey, look, if
you don't absolutely love what I'm
offering,
I'll give you your money back." Then
people go, "Oh, I don't need to trial it.
I don't need to jump on a phone call.
I'm just going to pay, and
if I don't like it,
I get my money back." There's a
mattress that I use called Nate Sleep.
I'm doing a YouTube video on it in a few
weeks.
Best mattress I've ever used in my life.
But it was like 2,500 US dollars,
and I was thinking, "Wow, can I really
spend that on a mattress?" 30-day,
no qualms, money-back guarantee.
It was like, fine. It's win-win now.
Either it's the best mattress of my life
or I'm getting my money back.
I might have an annoying trip to the post
office or some freight. It was amazing.
If they hadn't have offered that,
I probably wouldn't have had the mattress.
I wouldn't be making YouTube videos about
it, and I wouldn't be sleeping as well as
I am at the moment. Now,
if you want to be wealthy enough to afford
an Nate Sleep
mattress, well, your business
is going to have to level up a little bit.
So that 30-day business information over
30 days, clear up your inbox
for free,
there's one of the links in the
description.
And if you're ready to work with me,
where we can do deep dives into content,
strategy, squeezes, landing pages,
all of the above, my mentorship is
horrendously underpriced,
and I'm in there every day.
I even critique people's landing pages
individually.
You post a video in there,
and I'll be like, "Oh, your hook's shit,
your setup was
wrong, camera angle's not right,
your lighting's poo, your audio's not
good enough." I literally just kind of
bully a group of 1,250
people. But it's good bullying,
constructive bullying.
Tough love, some could say,
and some of them are absolutely killing
it.
So if you want that 30 days free business
advice, or you just want to jump straight
into the mentorship, the link's there.
If not,
feel free to comment in the comments,
and I'll be more than happy
to give you advice for free,
because I'm a nice guy.
Thanks for watching.